♪〜
I want to talk...
About your Wonderful Original
Interviews with Monster Girls
The class is astir
I want to let myself go too,
But I end up putting on a fake smile.
Your eyes alone conveyed a competitive spirit
Biting at your lip forcefully.
You once said,
"I wouldn't want to worry what someone thinks
And end up hurting someone else in the process!"
When the chime rings out, as the rain lifts up,
We'll pass the boundaries of our school!
Jumping through the puddles, light will scatter about
Our smiles, and wishes will be so bright!
I want to talk...
About your Wonderful Original!
〜♪
Demis Want to Try
Ms. Satou, drinking too much isn't good.
（早紀絵(さきえ)）〝佐藤(さとう)先生〞
〝飲みすぎは
よくないですよ〞
You should stop and get some sleep.
〝これくらいにして
そろそろ休みましょう〞
Oh, it's fine! Tomorrow's a day off!
（早紀絵）
いいじゃないですか！
明日も休みなんですし
（ゴク ゴク ゴク）
（早紀絵）ぷは〜っ　ハハッ
Mr. Takahashi!
高橋(たかはし)先生
ほ〜ら 高橋先生も もっと飲んで
大いに語り合いましょう
C'mon, Mr. Takahashi! Drink s'more,
and let's talk about how education oughta be!
教育のあるべき姿について
What a troublemaker.
“困った人ですね”
Little troublemakers like you require discipline.
“そんな困ったちゃんには
指導が必要かな？”
Discipline? What kind of discipline?
指導ですか？
指導って どんな？
Oh, no! Mr. Takahashi, not in the living room... You can't...
（バタン！）
（早紀絵）あっ そんな…
高橋先生 居間でなんて
そんな… あっ！
Ah, no! My triangle ruler...
あっ ダメ　三角定規が…
あ〜っ 三角の部分が…
The triangle part... Ah...
あっ 分度器も…
分度器もなんですか？
The protractor? You're using the protractor, too?
あっ チョーク… チョークもお願い
The chalk... And the chalk, please!
I'm being educated!
教育されちゃう〜！
あん
（バイブ音）
Hello?
（早紀絵）もしもし
Sorry, were you asleep?
（宇垣(うがき)）
悪い　寝てたか？
宇垣さん？
Ugaki?
No, I was studying some methods of discipline...
いえ ちょっと その
教育指導の勉強を…
Oh? You're so dedicated, even on the weekends.
（宇垣）
ほほう 休日だってのに熱心だな
Anyway, what's this about, Ugaki?
それより 宇垣さんこそ
どうしたんです？
Well, I was thinking about what happened the other day.
（宇垣）
いやなに ふと この間のことを
思い出してな
The other day?
（早紀絵）この間？
When you came to school with Kurtz?
クルツ君と学校に来たときですか？
The one you're interested in is Mr. Takahashi, isn't it?
（宇垣）
お前の気になる人って
高橋先生のことだろ？
H-How did you...
ど… どうして それを？
Bingo, huh?
（宇垣）やはりか
（早紀絵）あっ
But knowing you, you're standing by, doing nothing instead of acting, right?
だが お前のことだ
何か行動を起こすでもなく
手をこまねいているんだろ？
（早紀絵）
うっ
別に それを責めるつもりはない
I'm not criticizing you,
but I don't think you should go on like this.
だが このままでいいとも思わん
The time has come, Sakie!
時が来たのだ！
早紀絵 お前がサキュバスとして
ひと皮むけるときがな！
For you to show your true colors as a succubus!
はあ…
Uh-huh...
To be blunt, the reason you're slow to act
（宇垣）
ズバリ言うが お前の腰が重いのは
恋愛をするうえで
催淫することは避けられないが
is because you can't avoid your aphrodisiac effect in relationships.
But you don't want it to influence how you enter into them, right?
恋愛の過程に
催淫は持ち込みたくないという—
ジレンマだな
はい
Right...
I know you've always made it a point not to use your aphrodisiac effect
確かに 今までのお前は
みだりに他者を催淫すまいと
on others for your own gain.
それだけを考え 努めてきた
だから そう悩むのも分かる
So I understand your hesitation.
But now that a man has won your heart,
だが！　これからは
お前に好きなヤツができた以上
you need to accustom yourself to using your wiles on him!
意中の相手を催淫することにも
慣れていかなくては
ならないんじゃないか？
Am I wrong?
違うか？
Call forth the instincts of the succubus who devours men, night after night!
呼び起こせ
夜な夜な男を食らう
サキュバスの本能を！
That's only in the legends.
それは 伝承の話です
あと うるさいです
Also, stop yelling.
Still, you're right, Ugaki.
でも 宇垣さんの
おっしゃるとおりです
あ…？
Huh?
I know I need to change.
（早紀絵）
変わらなきゃいけないって
思います
恋愛をするためにも
So I can have a relationship.
好意とは どういうものか
折り合いをつけるためにも
And so that I can come to terms with what it means to like someone.
I can't keep running from my aphrodisiac effect.
催淫することから逃げてばかりでは
ダメなんだと思います
That's right.
そうだな
This is a good opportunity to try some things out.
いい機会だし
いろいろ やっていこうぜ
So go ahead and start doing things to seduce Mr. Takahashi tomorrow!
じゃあ 明日から どんどん
高橋先生を誘惑していこうな
Do I have to?
そうなりますか？
Of course you do!
そりゃそうだろ
The number of times you've seduced someone by chance is trivial, right?
だって 偶然に起こる催淫の数って
たかが知れてるだろ？
He'll get a girlfriend before you get accustomed to using your effect!
お前が催淫するのに慣れる前に
高橋先生に女ができちまうぞ
ううっ
And being half-assed about it won't even change the look on his face.
（宇垣）
あと 半端な催淫じゃ
高橋先生は
表情すら崩さないからな
If he has no reaction, you'll get no experience!
リアクションなきゃ
ちゃんと経験にならねえ！
So you need an individualistic approach to seducing him.
となると お前に
催淫する主体性が必要となる
In theory, I get what you're saying, but...
理屈は分かりますが…
I won't force you, but aren't you curious to see
まっ 強制はしないがな
でもさ ちょっと
見てみたいとは思わんか？
what Mr. Takahashi looks like when he's truly embarrassed?
高橋先生の本気でてれた姿
はっ
あの〜
Excuse me...
Ms. Satou?
（高橋）佐藤先生
Sorry...
（高橋）
すみません
てっきり ひかりか誰かかと
I thought you were Hikari or someone.
No, I'm sorry for suddenly walking in.
（早紀絵）
こちらこそ
急に お邪魔してしまいまして…
Oh, please take these to eat with the tea.
ああ これ お茶菓子にどうぞ
Shiba Shortbread
それで
So...
I thought I should talk to you about succubi.
一度ちゃんとサキュバスのことを
お話ししたいと思いまして
I was hoping it would help you.
先生のご参考になればと…
People like Mr. Takahashi crave knowledge not found in books.
高橋先生みたいなヤツは
書物の知識以上の
情報を求めるタイプだ
If you bring up the topic, he'll latch on!
お前から話を振れば 必ず食いつく
Huh? Really?
えっ ホントですか？
それは興味あります
I'm definitely interested.
（早紀絵）
食いついた
He latched on.
I don't get too many chances to learn about succubi from a succubus.
なかなか サキュバス本人から
お話を伺える機会はありませんから
I feel like books and documents just don't tell the whole story.
文献だけでは
どうも しっくりこないんですよね
What really counts is your timing in bringing up the subject!
そして お前が話を切り出す
タイミングが勝負だ！
Waste no time!
速攻！
Right!
（早紀絵）
ええい！
あっ
Oh!
Exactly like that!
（早紀絵）
ままよ！
Then, would you like to experience a bit of the succubus aphrodisiac effect?
じゃあ 少し体験してみますか？
サキュバスの催淫
Huh?
へ？
Okay, if you'll excuse me a moment...
（早紀絵）
じゃあ ちょっと失礼して…
Wait, what are you doing?
（高橋）えっ ちょっと何を？
Oh, I'm just taking off a layer. Don't worry.
（早紀絵）
あっ 少し薄着になるだけなんで
大丈夫で〜す
Oh, you are...
Wait, you are?
そうですか？
（早紀絵）はい じゃじゃ〜ん
Yep!
Ta-dah!
Wh-What do you think?
ど… どうですかね？
Kill me now!
（早紀絵）
死にたい
Uh... Well, I think you look very nice.
ええ その…
すごくステキだと思います
It completely changes your image, huh?
随分 雰囲気 変わるものですね
Thank you...
ありがとうございます
Hardly any reaction at all!
（早紀絵）
リアクションが薄い
This doesn't feel anything like using my aphrodisiac effect.
確かに これじゃ
催淫した気にならない
It's just making me anxious...
というよりも 不安になってしまう
Do I really even have an aphrodisiac effect?
本当に催淫の効果 あるのかしら？
Damn, she's sexy!
（高橋）
エッロ〜
It's like I can physically see the sex appeal!
色気が可視化されて見えるようだ
I actually feel like I've reverted back to a hormonal teenager.
学生のころの性欲が
戻った気さえする
I'd better try not to look at her whole body like normal.
いつものように
全体を見ないようにしよう
I'll just focus on the spot right above her eyes...
目の少し上の辺りだけを こう…
Wow, her hair looks so silky...
髪ツヤツヤだな〜
あっ 違う
Wait, no!
しかし 着こなしだけで
こうも変わるとは…
I can't believe a little clothing makes this much difference.
Now I see how thorough she normally is.
いかに ふだんが
徹底されているかが分かるな
With her usual look, as long as I don't touch her, I feel nothing.
あの姿なら
触れられでもしないかぎりは
何も感じない
あっ
I just had a thought...
（高橋）ふと思ったのですが
（早紀絵）はい
Yes?
Couldn't you dress a bit more casually on a regular basis?
ふだんから もう少しラフな格好を
されてもいいんじゃないですか？
（早紀絵）えっ？
Huh?
（高橋）
毎日それだけ気を遣うと
窮屈でしょう
It must be suffocating, being so careful every day.
If you loosen up a tiny bit,
多少 隙があるくらいなら
your aphrodisiac effect won't be problematic, right?
何か問題になるほど
催淫することもないのでは？
U-Um, well...
え… え〜っとですね
Mr. Takahashi,
あの 高橋先生は
do you think feelings of affection for a succubus can be real?
サキュバスに向けられる好意は
本物だと思いますか？
本物？
Real?
I mean... I think the aphrodisiac effect
何ていうか
サキュバスに向けられる好意って
just jacks up any feelings one has for a succubus.
催淫によってゲタを履かせた
状態だと思うんです
The reason I go to such lengths is because
ふだん 極端に催淫を避けるのも
I want to avoid influencing men to develop such feelings for me.
そういう好意を
向けられるのが嫌で…
（高橋）う〜ん
This is purely my own opinion.
これは あくまで私の考えですが
O-Okay.
（早紀絵）あっ はい
First, the difference between normal women and succubi,
（高橋）
そもそも普通の女性と
サキュバスの違いですが
in my mind, is practically nonexistent, besides the inborn nature of succubi.
私の理屈では 夢魔の特性以外は
ほとんど変わりありません
Normal women can also drastically change their appeal
普通の女性だって
先ほどの佐藤先生のように
服装のいかんによって
魅力は大きく左右します
with some clothing, like you did just now.
So what is the difference?
では 何が異なるのかというと
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Clothes on
Clothes off
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Clothes on
Clothes off
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Clothes on
Clothes off
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Clothes on
Clothes off
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Clothes on
Clothes off
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Clothes on
Clothes off
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Clothes on
Clothes off
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Clothes on
Clothes off
It's this margin.
この差です
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Clothes on
Clothes off
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Clothes on
Normal Women
Clothes off
Succubi
Clothes on
Normal Women
Clothes off
Succubi
Clothes on
Normal Women
Clothes off
Succubi
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Sexiness
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Normal Women
Clothes on
Clothes off
Succubi
Basically, a succubus's aphrodisiac effect is a matter of degree.
つまり サキュバスの催淫とは
程度の差なのです
Can we work with this assumption?
という認識で進めてもいいですか？
Sure. Please continue.
はい 続けてください
That being the case, what remains is the perception of this margin.
（高橋）
だとすれば あとは
この差をどう捉えるかです
A moment ago, you expressed this difference
佐藤先生は 先ほど この差を
as feelings that are "jacked up," but I don't see it that way.
ゲタを履かせていると
表現しましたが
私は そう思いません
Physical allure varies with time and place, the situation, and one's condition.
コンディションやシチュエーション
時と場合によって変わる魅力
Just as those combine for one's physical allure,
全て ひっくるめて
その人の魅力であるように
I think your aphrodisiac effect is part of your allure, too.
佐藤先生の魅力も また
催淫込みで
あなたの魅力なんだと思います
In other words, I don't think there's any such thing as fake feelings for someone.
つまり 好意にニセモノはない
というのが 私なりの答えです
In my opinion, as an actual succubus...
（早紀絵）私の考えはですね
サキュバス本人としては…
Yes? Please share.
はい 教えてください
（早紀絵）
ああ 楽しいな こういうの
This is kind of fun.
Sharing our ideas, respecting one another,
お互いの考えを語り合って
尊重し合って
and looking for common ground.
落としどころを探したりして
And what makes it fun isn't that we're talking about succubi.
そして 楽しいのは
サキュバスの
話題だからってわけじゃない
I guess I just really like him.
やっぱり… 好きなんだろうな
It might be unfair to Ugaki, after he gave me a push,
背中を押してくれた
宇垣さんには悪いけど
but I won't use my aphrodisiac effect, after all.
やっぱり
自分から催淫するのは よそう
Mr. Takahashi responds to me with sincerity.
高橋先生は 真摯(しんし)に答えてくれる人
なら私も 真摯に臨むべきだと思う
So I think I should try to be sincere, too.
I know what Mr. Takahashi said,
高橋先生は ああ言ってくれたけど
but using my aphrodisiac effect is beyond my ability.
As long as I'm aware of that, I shouldn't use it.
But someday, I hope I can find some common ground with it,
でも いつか
“ここまでは使っていい”
so I'll know to what extent I can use it.
催淫にも そういう落としどころが
見つかるといいな
あっ
ん？
ううっ ううっ…
Sorry about that.
（早紀絵）すみませんでした
（高橋）いいえ
No problem.
Maybe I can use just that much of it.
（早紀絵）
ここまでだったら
使ってもいいかな
And so...
That's how I got to see Mr. Takahashi embarrassed!
（宇垣）
よかったじゃないか
Good for you.
And we shared our opinions about succubi with each other...
それにサキュバスの性質についても
お互いの意見を言い合ったりして
なんだ 考え方が違うのか？
What, you two have differing opinions?
You gonna be okay like that?
大丈夫か？　そんなんで
You've got it all wrong!
（早紀絵）
違いますよ！
考え方が違うから いいんですよ！
It's good that our opinions differ!
You just don't understand, Ugaki!
分かってないですね 宇垣さんは
I see.
（宇垣）そうすか
That's how we can consider each other's positions.
（早紀絵）
だから お互いの立場も
考えつつとか
いろいろ 議論が
白熱しちゃいましたが
We got into some heated discussions,
それで 結局
落としどころとしてはですね…
but in the end, as a common ground...
Thanks for the report. Later.
（宇垣）
報告 ご苦労さん
じゃあ またな
Satou Sakie
フウ
I wonder if this is what the melancholy of watching a daughter grow up is like.
娘が巣立っていく寂しさって…
Interviews with Monster Girls
こんなのかな〜
また 高橋先生と議論を深めたい
I want to have another deep discussion with Mr. Takahashi.
But would it only be an excuse to see him again?
でも それって“また会いたい”
っていう言い訳なのかな
If I could control my aphrodisiac effect, this wouldn't be a problem...
催淫をコントロールできれば
苦労はしないんだろうけど
What would you do if you could?
（雪(ゆき)）
催淫をコントロールして何を？
どわ〜っ 雪ちゃん！
Y-Yuki!
何か いかがわしい
臭いがしますが…
Something smells fishy to me.
Y-You've got it all wrong!
（早紀絵）ち… 違うのよ！
You know my nature inconveniences me in multiple ways, don't you?
ほら こういう性質って
いろいろと生活に不便があるでしょ
That's why I...
だから…
Oh, yes, that's definitely true.
ああ それは確かに そうですね
（早紀絵）ハア
So, did you need to talk to me?
で 私に何か用？
Here's the thing we discussed.
（雪）これ 例の物です
The Amazing
Van Deursen
（早紀絵）わあ！
This looks correct.
間違いないようね
Here are the ones I've finished reading.
これ 読み終えた分
Got them.
（雪）確かに受け取りました
I truly thank you, Yuki.
ホントにありがとうね 雪ちゃん
We are kindred spirits, after all!
同好の士… ですから！
Excuse me.
（雪）失礼しました
コントロールか…
Control, huh?
雪女の性質を
コントロールしたい？
You want to control your snow woman attributes?
Yes.
はい 自分の意思で ある程度
I think it would be nice if I could generate cold air voluntarily.
冷気を出せるように
なったらいいなって
I've always thought it was strange
冷気を出せる体質があるのに
to have to worry about overheating, since I can create cold air.
暑さに悩むのは変だなって
前から思っていて…
I see your point.
うん 一理ある
（雪）フウ
Well, it is almost summer.
夏も近いし やってみるか！
Why don't you try?
あっ
フフッ
This kind of brings back memories.
懐かしいですね この感じ
ハハ 初心に帰って
というところだな
Sort of like going back to square one, huh?
To review,
おさらいだが
snow women's unique traits come from negative emotion.
雪女の性質は
ネガティブな感情に起因している
The cold sweat from nerves or stress,
緊張やストレスによってかく
冷や汗や
as well as tears you shed when sad, become ice.
悲しいことによって流す涙は 凍る
And when you're very depressed, you generate cold air, right?
そして ひどく落ち込んだりすると
冷気が出る
だな？
Right!
はい！
We can save the intricate control for later.
細かいコントロールは 後々にして
For now, let's work on generating your own cold air.
当面は なんとか身ひとつで
冷気を出すことを目指そう
Right.
（雪）はい！
You may work up a cold sweat doing this,
その間に 冷や汗を
かくかもしれないから
so we'll catch it in the basin.
タライで受け取ってと…
Then, what should I do, specifically?
それで 具体的には
どうしたらいいんですか？
Hmm... You can generate cold air when sad,
う〜ん 悲しい気持ちになれば
冷気は出るが
but you want to be able to do so without being sad...
最終的には それによらず
冷気を出したい
Why not try pretending?
ふりをしてみるか？
（雪）ふり？
（高橋）つまり演技だな
Pretending?
In other words, acting.
To learn if you can create cold air with artificial negative emotion.
（高橋）
擬似的に作ったネガティブな感情で
冷気が出るかどうか
Acting? So I should act like I'm sad?
演技？
ネガティブな悲しい演技を？
Yeah, like...
そうだ　こう…
"Ah, something has happened to Hikari and Machi."
“あ〜 ひかりや町(まち)に
何かあった〜”とか
Create something like that.
何か設定を考えて
うっ ああ… えっ えっと〜
Ah... U-Um...
ク…
Darn it... How dare you do that to them?!
クッソ〜 よくも２人を〜
悲しいよ〜
I'm so sad!
（高橋）フフッ 何だそりゃ？
What the heck is that?
How can this be? How can this be?
Wait, I shouldn't laugh. That's rude.
（高橋）
あっ いかん いかん
笑ったら失礼だな
Yuki's serious about this.
雪は 真面目にやってるのに
Curse you!
おのれ〜！
That's a convincing act!
（高橋）
迫真！　別の能力に
覚醒しそうな勢いだ
At this rate, she might learn a new ability.
I'm so sad! It hurts so much!
（雪）悲しいよ〜
An ability, huh?
（高橋）
能力か…
Biologically, it's impossible for a snow woman's bodily fluids
雪女の体が冷たいからといって
to be near freezing, just because she has a low body temperature.
体液が氷点に近いというのは
生物としてありえない
When she experiences negative emotion,
雪女がネガティブな感情にあるとき
something acts on her cold sweat at the moment it leaves her body, freezing it.
Something
何かが 体外に出る瞬間の冷や汗に
働きかけて凍らせるのだ
Something
Tears
Sweat
Generation of cold air must also be a result of freezing the air around her.
冷気を出すという性質も
つまりは 何かが周りの空気を
冷やしているということだろう
Air
But what is that "something"?
何かとは 何か？
Negative emotion implies volition.
ネガティブな感情とは つまり意思
Wait, if it's possible to define "volition" physically,
待てよ？　意思に物理的な定義が
できるのだとしたら…
Curse you!
that would also explain how a succubus's aphrodisiac effect
催淫という他者の意思に
影響を及ぼす サキュバスの性質も
Curse... Curse you!
influences the volition of others.
物理的に説明がつく
I'd like to check with Ms. Satou on that...
佐藤先生に確認したいところだな
（雪）ハア ハア…
I wish... I wish you'd notice right about now
（雪）
そろそろ…
そろそろ気付いてほしい
how embarrassing this whole scenario is.
この状態が
とても恥ずかしいことに
I forgot. When we ask him for help on demi matters,
忘れていた
デミのことを相談すると
Mr. Takahashi becomes so engrossed,
高橋先生は
その１点に夢中になって
his sense of delicacy stops working.
デリカシーが
活動を止めてしまうのだ
Mr. Takahashi, can I stop now?
高橋先生 もうそろそろ…
Huh? Oh, yeah.
（高橋）ん？　あっ そうだな
Hmm, I don't feel any cold air.
う〜む 冷気は出てないみたいだな
演技ではダメか
I guess acting doesn't work.
Oh, but you worked up lots of cold sweat.
おっ 冷や汗は 結構 出てるな
そうですね
Yes, I did.
Yeah, because I'm so embarrassed.
（雪）
それは 恥ずかしくて
かいたものです
Let's not try this method again.
この方法は
これっきりにしましょう
It didn't create cold air!
冷気は出ません
You're right.
そうだな
（扉が開く音）
Heya, heya!
（ひかり）やほやほ〜！　ん？
Hikari?
（雪）ひかり？
（高橋）おう
Hey.
What're you guys up to?
（ひかり）何してるの？
We were trying to think of a way
いや 雪女の力で
来(きた)るべく暑さをしのぐ方法を
考えていたんだが…
she can use her snow woman power to beat the heat this summer.
あっ いや〜
それが全然うまくいかなくて
Yeah, but it didn't work out at all!
ん？　そう？
No? But you created that ice, didn't you?
それ ユッキーの出した氷でしょ？
Huh?
（雪）えっ？
（ひかり･町）ハア〜
It feels so nice and cool!
（町）冷たくて気持ちいい
暑さ しのげる〜
Now, this is beating the heat!
Well, I guess that's our result for today.
まっ 今日の成果は
ここまでということで
Yukki, the ice is melting.
ユッキー
氷が溶けちゃう 溶けちゃう
Curse you!
（雪）おのれ〜！
Split into two teams and practice passing.
（教師Ａ）
２組に分かれて パスの練習
Man, it's so hot today...
（佐竹(さたけ)）
しっかし 今日は めちゃ暑いな
The rainy season ended early, too.
（太田(おおた)）
梅雨 明けるのも早かったし
This year, summer is gonna be a lot hotter.
今年は猛暑になるそうだ… ぞ！
か〜 マジかよ
Are you serious?
こんなクッソ暑い日に
外で体育なんて やってらんね〜
I can't handle outdoor P.E. class on hot days like this!
（ピッ）
（教師Ｂ）女子集合
Girls, gather round!
（女子たち）は〜い
Yes, ma'am!
Today, we're timing you on a middle-distance, 1.5-kilometer run.
（教師Ｂ）
今日は 中距離1,5キロの
タイムを測るよ
Running your hardest at the start is dangerous.
いきなり全力で走ると危ないので
その前に軽くグランドを…
So we'll jog a few laps first to get your bodies used to it.
Nothing beats P.E. class in summer!
やっぱり 夏は体育に限るな〜
Okay, start with three laps around the field.
You don't even try to hide that side of you?
お前って ホント
そういうの隠す気ないのな
Yes, ma'am!
ハア ハア ハア…
If you have trouble seeing, let me know.
（教師Ｂ）
見づらかったら言いなね
（町）はい
Okay.
（ひかり･雪）ハア ハア…
The sun is killing me...
日ざし めっちゃ きついんだけど…
（雪）こんなの… もう 真夏だよ
It's like the middle of summer already...
今日も暑いな
Another hot day...
Hello.
（町）こんにちは
（高橋）ん？
Oh, hey, Machi. P.E. class?
（高橋）
おう 町 こんにちは
体育か？
Yes, we're together with class A.
はい Ａ組との合同でした
Then, Yuki's with you?
じゃあ 雪も一緒か
Must've been noisy with you three together.
いつもの３人組で
やかましかったろ
フフフ
Actually...
それが…
（２人）ああ…
So hot...
あっつ〜
Excuse us!
（３人）失礼しま〜す
うわ〜 生き返る〜
I feel alive again!
It's heaven.
極楽
Compared to that hell earlier, this is heaven for sure!
さっきの地獄に比べれば
ここは まさに極楽だよ
P.E. class outside must've been rough.
（高橋）
外の体育 つらそうだったな
Yes, extremely!
はい そりゃもう
You must be in a pretty cushy position to have air conditioning, Mr. T.
（ひかり）
いつもながら 冷房完備とは
いいご身分ですな 先生！
Well, there are things in here that shouldn't get too warm.
まあ ここには
暖めすぎちゃマズいもんが…
Oh, I guess I explained that before.
あっ これ 前も言ったな
Try not to hang around in here too much.
あんまり ここに
居座らないようにしろよ
I know you ladies don't handle heat well, but all things in moderation.
暑さに弱いお嬢さん方には悪いが
程々にな
Huh? But in summer, being a vampire really sucks...
え〜 夏のバンパイア
ホント大変なのに
It isn't easy for a snow woman, either.
それを言ったら 雪女だって
（２人）むっ
It's a lot harder on vampires.
バンパイアのほうが大変です〜
We sunburn easily, so we can't wear short sleeves,
腕 日焼けしやすいから
半袖 着られないし〜
and the sun is way too bright!
太陽も まぶしすぎるんです〜
Well, it's hard for a snow woman, too!
雪女だって大変です〜
Our body temperatures are low,
体温が低い分
体感温度は高いんです
so high temperatures feel even hotter!
And we almost never sweat, either!
汗も あんまりかかないし〜
（２人）プッ
（ひかり）ハハハ
（雪）ハハハ 何なの もう
What was that?
（高橋）汗で滑ったりしないか？
（町）あっ はい
Doesn't the sweat make your hands slippery?
Well, my hands don't sweat much, but...
手汗は あまりかかないので
でも…
あっ 先生 もっと涼しくするための
提案があります
Mr. T! I have an idea for how we can make it even cooler!
Oh? What's that? Let's hear it.
おっ 何だ？　言うてみよ
スイカ食べたいから 買って！
I want some watermelon, so go buy one!
How overbearing can you be?!
（高橋）厚かましいにも程がある！
（ひかり）うわ〜 にゃ〜
Meow!
ハア
涼みたいなら
そのテンションをどうにかしろ
If you want to cool off, try being a little less hyper.
And watermelons are pretty expensive, you know.
まだ結構するんだ スイカも
まったく…
あっ
Actually, I think there were some leftover popsicles in the faculty office...
そういえば 職員室に
アイスの余っていたやつが…
Too easy.
（ひかり）甘い！
（町）優しい
He's so nice.
I think he just doesn't want to spend any money.
（雪）
というか 単に
自腹を切りたくないだけでは？
Aren't there any other ways to cool down?
ほかに何か涼しくなる方法は
ないかな？
How about your "curse you," Yuki?
雪ちゃんの“おのれ〜”は？
No, that's too tiring.
いや あれは疲れるから
Aw, but I liked "curse you."
え〜っ 私は好きだけどな
“おのれ”
When did you name it that?
（雪）
その呼び名は いつ決まったの？
う〜ん “おのれ〜”みたいに
I wish there were something we could do anytime, like "curse you."
いつでもできることだと
いいんだけどな
Stop thinking you can do that anytime!
（雪）
いつでもできるとか思わないで
There's no AC in the classrooms,
教室にもエアコンないし
so if there were a way we could cool off with others...
人がいればできる
涼しくなること…
Maybe ghost stories?
怪談… とか？
Ghost stories! Classic!
怪談！　渋い
To send a chill down the spine, right?
背中をゾクッと凍らせる
ということですな
（町）うん
Yeah.
Okay, Macchi, tell us one!
じゃあ マッチー 一席お願い
Making someone else do it again?
（雪）また そんなムチャぶりを
Not long ago, I found this one online.
この前 ネットで
見たやつなんだけど
Oh, you're doing it?
（雪）あっ やるんだ
It was a hot, muggy day, just like today.
（町）
それは 今日みたいに
蒸し暑い日でした
Two girls with highly adventurous spirits
冒険心の強い ２人組の女の子が
visited a cave said to be the site of a long ago murder.
かつて殺人事件があったと
ウワサされる—
洞窟へ やってきました
The two had only their small, hand-held lights
２人は 光の差さない
真っ暗な洞窟を
to guide them through the darkness,
手にした明かりだけを頼りに
一歩一歩 進んでいきました
as they continued through the cave, one step at a time.
They were no longer sure how far they had walked,
それから 一体
どれだけ歩いたことでしょう？
when they arrived at a split in the path.
やがて ２人は
分かれ道に たどりついたのです
There, as if someone had foreseen their arrival,
そこには まるで誰かが来るのを
知っていたかのように
they found a written note.
書き置きがありました
I killed someone.
I cut them in two at the neck.
I took the head down the left path,
and the body down the right path.
I killed someone.
I cut them in two at the neck.
I took the head down the left path,
and the body down the right path.
I killed someone.
I cut them in two at the neck.
I took the head down the left path,
and the body down the right path.
They felt that seeing a severed head would be scary,
生首を見るのは怖いと思い
so they decided to take the right path.
２人は 右の道を
進むことにしました
Far along the right path, just as the note said,
右の道の奥には 書き置きのとおり
首のない死体がありました
they found a headless body.
They felt a bit relieved.
少しホッとする２人でしたが
But then they found another note next to the body.
死体の傍らには
またしても書き置きが…
ひとつ
The head is coming up behind you.
（女性のうめき声）
（町）ああ〜 ああ〜
（雪･ひかり）プッ
（雪･ひかり）アハハハ
（町）あれ？
That isn't scary at all!
（ひかり）全然 怖くない
（雪）ねっ
No!
（ひかり）ハア…
I guess the scary story failed.
（雪）怖い話作戦は 失敗だね
Come to think of it, Macchi, you're wearing a vest.
あっ そういや マッチー
ベスト着てるね
Huh?
（町）えっ？
（雪）ホントだ　暑くないの？
Oh, yeah. Aren't you hot?
うん まあ…
着てないよりかは暑いかな？
Oh, well... Hotter than I'd be without it, I guess.
（２人）ん？
Don't you get sweaty?
汗 かいちゃわない？
Or don't you sweat, Kyouko?
京子(きょうこ) 汗かかないほうだっけ？
No, actually, I think I sweat quite a lot.
ううん むしろ
汗っかきなほうだと思う
Then why are you wearing a vest?
（ひかり）
じゃあ なんでベスト着てるの？
Um... Well, because...
えっと つまり その…
When I sweat, my underclothes show through my shirt.
汗かくと シャツが透けちゃって
下着が見えちゃうから
（２人）うわあ おお…
おお！
Hey!
（高橋）お〜い
I brought popsicles...
アイス持ってきてやった…
ぞ？
for you?
Welcome back.
（ひかり･雪）おかえりなさい
They're frozen!
（高橋）冷えきっている
♪〜
The events of a mysterious world,
Like the ones you hear of in fairy tales,
Are actually closer than you think
Just like the way you and I met!
When I stood up tall to gaze at
The familiar scenery outside my window,
Even days that felt like torture seemed precious somehow.
Stuck in my heart, I can't put them into words
How should I try to put these feelings into words?
Laughing over stupid things...
Getting mad over small details...
We'll keep carving these trivial moments into our hearts.
Sometimes I'm feeling sad...
But when I'm with you, I'm so happy!
We'll keep on building these irreplaceable moments,
〜♪
And little by little, we'll come to understand one another.
The Dullahan Surpasses Space-Time
Next Time
（ひまり）
次回「亜人ちゃんは
語りたい」
Next time on Interviews with Monster Girls:
The Dullahan Surpasses Space-Time.